Contact: turkision@gmail.com
Thanks to my Allah, He let us see these days.
What else could I expect?
If we are allies now, then..
...we should seek fights and conquests.
We should. May our alliance be forever,
if Allah permits!
Bring the bards! Play music!
Sing songs! Come on! Come on!
Kanyumaz, send messages to beys immediately.
Tell them Osman Bey pledged loyalty
and he's with us now.
As you order my Bey.
My Bey, messenger of Mugla is here.
How dare you come in without permission?
Who are you? How dare you come into my tent like this?
I take my daring from the Ilkhanid State.
I'm the messenger of Olcaytu Khan.
Who do you take your daring from, Yakup Bey?
You can have the daring.
Who did you take permission from
and you declared yourself as the sultan?
Only Emirs take permissions, not Sultans.
Tell me about your matter...
...and you may have a long life, Messenger!
If you come forward as the sultan,
..then you have to pay tax.
Now you will pay the tax that
Sultan Mesud has paid so far.
Stop there!
How could you demand the tax Yakup Bey didn't collect?
You came down here like a vulture!
You must be Osman.
Yes. If you know my name,
you must also know about my reputation.
I know. I know.
You gave our commanders and governors a hard time.
-Is Osman Bey with you, Yakup Bey?
-He is.
We have alliance in our land.
Good. Good.
Apart from your yearly tax 50.000 dirham gold coins,
...you will pay 20.000 dirhams more
as the price of the blood Osman shed.
-You have two days.
-Messenger!
Look at me. If you go beyond being a messenger...
...and try to rule,
...you will lose your head.
My words are Olcaytu Khan's words.
You shouldn't tell me things that you can't say to him.
You have two days.
Everything you own...
...is yours as long as we want to.
-Don't, Osman Bey.
-Shh...
When we become a state, you will see who's going to pay taxes.
If I bleed,
...this land which you call homeland...
...will be a blood bath.
Come on, do it.
Osman Bey!
Now go! Your gold will come after you!
Two days. Or we'll take it as a riot and destroy you!
Osman Bey!
While you were buying the stands today...
While you were handing out gold coins to people,
you were very carefree.
70.000 dirhams.
As 20.000 is already your price,
...you will pay this tax.
-Help us, my Allah!
-Hold on, brother.
We'll find out who stole the gold and made a slaughter here.
Hold on, brother! Hold on!
You! Are you alright?
I'm fine, my Bey. It's nothing.
We should go see the healer!
Hold on, brother!
That gold will be your death, Bayindir.
Yakup Bey, is this...
..a punishment for me? Or a request?
I should know this first.
Osman Bey, you pledged loyalty.
It's neither a request nor a punishment. It's an order.
Battle is a wedding for us.
A wedding of 70.000 gold coins, huh?
These lands have never seen such a rich wedding.
Keep the other beys out of this. I will pay this for our unity.
For sure, I have enough to pay.
Alright then, Osman Bey.
If you are the Sultan
...you should take care of this tax matter.
Well... Konya collapsed due to the taxes.
If we keep paying this tax,
...nobody can stand this. You should know.
Don't worry.
Everything has a time.
As we kept saying this,
...the enemy jumped on us!
This is our last tax. Gather the beys
and recruit the army.
We'll either come forward like true men
and get rid of our chains...
...or go out of existence for ever.
If you are the Sultan, you'll make the choice.
You go do your duty. I'll do what a Sultan should do.
Bards, play and sing!
Tell me.
Osman Bey.
It doesn't look like good news.
Something troublesome came up.
I hope it's not something to keep you
away from your duty.
No. It won't stop my duty. But we'll be there
at dawn only if we leave now.
-I should go.
-Osman Bey.
Prepare the gold.
Don't disgrace yourself or us against the enemy.
Hold on, brother. Brother?
They... They stole the gold.
-What?
-The gold..
O Shafi (The Healer)! O Allah!
Hold on, brother. Hold on.
We put the gold where you ordered, Master Gera.
What's in your mind, Master Gera?
Cerkutay.
He hates Osman. Boran..
He's fighting for his life.
Our next man is Bayindir Bey.
I will take him away from Osman harshly.
Osman will remain all alone.
We'll do that by using the gold.
The gold... They must be looking for it everywhere.
They will leave no rocks unturned.
Veysel Alp, they will interrogate you too.
Go to the palace in no time.
You will start the game.
What's the situation? Where is Boran?
My Bey.
Konur Bey was at the headquarters.
And I was dealing with the trading books of the stands.
-And?
My Bey, Boran Bey was here.
They stole all the gold and the treasure.
What are you saying?
All the alps guarding it and Boran Bey are in the healing house.
Counting on the gold
...I said I'd pay the tax to Mongolians.
Someone who knew about the treasure did this.
They used the goods entrance.
Yes. Our alps know when the goods are coming in and out.
We weren't expecting any goods in the palace.
So you say it's not weakness, but betrayal.
-You say it's betrayal, huh?
-Yes, my Bey.
With your permission,
we should stop the raids in the west.
-Yes. We should retreat the scouts and Yenisehir...
-Enough!
Will we give up as they hit our treasure? Ha?
Will we stop as they hit our palace and the house?
No way! No!
If any of you feels afraid or doubts,
...he can wait for his death in the arms of his wife!
Nobody will retreat! Close all the exits of Yenisehir.
You'll check come comes in and goes out.
If you suspect anyone,
...you will search thoroughly!
-As you order, my Bey.
My Bey
-Speak.
-My Bey.
I heard a location's name when I was wounded.
-Orhan.
-My Bey.
You'll go where Veysel mentions and you'll
find the gold and the traitor.
-As you order, my Bey.
-But...
-You'll go with him.
-As you order, my Bey.
Come on, son.
GERMIYANOGULLARI BORDER
Osman's loyalty is not genuine.
He is just trying to buy time.
Do not fall into carelessness.
Keep your eyes peeled.
That is why gave that tax to Osman as a burden.
Learn well to play tricks from your father, my Mehmet.
I do mother, I do. Act unsuspicious
so they stay close to you.
So that they can stay right beneath your
hands for you to break their necks.
Let them pay their taxes to Mongols..
With the money they got from the treasure of Konya.
-Does Osman Bey has the treasure, father?
-If he doesn't have it..
How could he buy the stalls.
Undertake all those taxes.
Then Orhan was the one hitting me.
I will choke him with my own hands. And I will..
You won't! Don't, Mehmet.
I did my every move with politics.
You will act with politics as well.
I do not want any other moves.
We know the move we are going to make, my Bey.
Since I got my homage from all the beys..
I will wear the robe of Sultanship.
I will give away coins and make my name..
Famous all over the earth in khutbah.
-Am I allowed, Yakup Bey.
-Come in Kutay, come in.
Good morning. Yakup Bey..
-You wanted me.
-Cerkutay.
Yakup Bey! Yakup Bey!
They attacked Osman Bey's palace, that's why they left.
They say his Alp Boran Bey got wounded badly, lingering.
-Does anyone know who did it?
-No one knows, my Bey.
Hatun, get ready quickly. We are going to
Osman Bey to wish him speedy recovery.
Yakup Bey.
With your permission, I shall return to my post.
The enemy is looking for excuses to destroy our land.
If we can not give the gold to Mongols on time,
we'll have to give this excuse ourselves.
They will accuse me for it as well.
As I said there is no need for Beys..
I will pay the tax off.
Now they will accuse me for this war
that is about to break down.
The treasure will surely be found.
However, we have to count the worst scenarios.
-Bayindir.
-My Bey.
Check how much fortresses and castles have money.
To the shops that can be sold..
And even horses. We will give everything we have.
We will not be looked down upon
by our enemies and Yakup Bey.
-As you command, my Bey.
-Konur.
You will have the palace searched again.
As we have a traitor among us..
-We will find him.
-As you command, my Bey.
My Bey, my Bey, My Osman Bey.
-Boran Bey can not breathe.
-What are you saying.
Alaeddin.
-Boran Bey, hang on. Breathe, Boran Bey.
-Boran!
What happened? Healer! Tell me!
My Bey, he had two or three wounds.
We closed and cleaned them all. He was alright...
-But...
-But what?
Now... He cannot breathe, my Bey.
-What is happening? What is happening Alaeddin?
-Any broken bones? Did you check?
Hold him. Turn him over. Turn him.
Come on Boran Bey.
-Hang on brother.
-Come on!
Broken bone... It was stuck there.
Thanks to Allah, he can breathe now.
-He will lay on his one side for some time.
-Yes my Shahzade.
My Bey.
My valiant.
What happened? How did they do this to you?
-He'll be alright, right?
-I hope so, my Bey, I hope so.
He'll be alright. Hang on, Boran. My valiant.
Don't you leave... Look...
Do you remember what you told me?
You said, "My Bey...
..all the things I know will go to grave with me.
" Don't you do that...
Don't... Don't... It's not time.
You cannot go anywhere. Alright?
You cannot go.
Alaeddin... Boran is entrusted to you, my son.
Yes my Bey.
But... I don't know how long he can resist...
...and if he survives until tomorrow, my Bey.
GERMIYANOGULLARI BORDER - FRONTIER BAZAAR
Mother! Mother!
They are going to Osman Bey's palace. Let's go!
-I am curious, mother.
-Stop, my boy.
My dear... I am also curious, I also want to go there.
You are scared of that Cerkutay, right, mother?
Cerkutay Bey! We want to go to Osman Bey's palace!
We will see my uncle Boran. We will go.
Cerk... -We won't go.
My dear... Go to Yakub Bey. Come on.
My Cerkutay...
Don't you think I know that you are suffering?
Come on, don't be stubborn. Let's go.
Boran is your brother. Don't leave him alone.
Brother? Brother, huh?
A brother who thought I was dead...
..and left me behind. No.
None of you understand what I've been through.
Even you.
Cerkutay..
May Allah not let it happen early, but...
...what if Boran
Bey passes away?
The ones I called "My Bey" and "my brothers"..
.left me.
I will ignore them now.
Cerkutay Bey. Come on. You are coming with us.
Yakub Bey, if you allow us...
I said come on, Cerkutay. We are going together.
He said we are going.
Peace and Allah's mercy and blessings
shall be upon you.
-Peace be upon you too.
-Forgive me, please.
I mean, I couldn't help it, I came here after
I heard what happened.
You did good. Thank you, Ayhan Agha, but...
-How did you hear it?
-Everyone heard it.
Everyone is talking about this.
Did you lose a lot?
Please, do not misunderstand me, Bayindir Bey...
I owe a life to Osman Bey .
I did not come here to express my wishes.
Whatever the casualty is, I want to do my best.
Thank you Ayhan Agha. Thank you.
Good then. Let's go to Osman Bey...
...and he will tell you the most suitable thing.
-Sure. Sure.
-Come.
-Here.
Go.
Tell me my Fatma. Is Boran Bey alright?
I hope he will be alright, mother.
My Alaeddin brother is taking care of him.
That's why he couldn't visit you. Don't be offended.
I know, my beautiful daughter. I know.
How can children offend their mothers anyway?
Which mother's heart can take it?
You will drink these in the morning and at night.
My brother thinks about you all the time.
He loves you in a different way, mother.
Yes... He does for now, but...
...once he falls in love, you'll see how he forgets his mother.
He won't. Besides, if he could, he would already.
So you are saying that your brother
Alaeddin is already in love, huh?
-No... I didn't say that.
-You did.
I didn't, mother.
-You did, you did.
Who is that girl?
That's the issue, mother.
I will tell you, but you will not tell my brother. Promise me.
Promise, my daughter. Come on, tell me.
Germiyanoglu Yakub Bey's daughter Gonca.
-Fatma, what are you saying?
-I saw my brother’s eyes.
He loves that girl.
Yakub Bey and his family.. It is too hard.
-It is too hard, my Fatma.
-I know, I know mother.
And since my father pledged allegiance...
What if it is a trap? Huh?
-Do you think that girl is reliable?
-I don't know.
Come on. We are going to Yenisehir.
Now? Are you serious, mother?
I cannot rest and stay here anymore. Come on.
This is the end of the tracks.
-We will go into the forest and keep searching!
-Yes my Shahzade. Come on valiants!
My Shahzade!
They dropped their servant suits here.
They snuck into the palace with these.
They took out their dresses and went.
But where did they go?
You are watchful Veysel. Once again you won my favor.
They removed the traces of the cars.
Then they must have gone this way my Shahzade.
Come on.
Osman Bey, I heard about the incident you experienced.
I hope it gets better soon.
-Thank you Ayhan Agha, thank you.
-Is there anything I can do?
You don't have many losses I hope.
Osman Bey, I don't want to be misunderstood.
I'm not only here to offer you my best wishes.
I can make front payment
for the caravan that you agreed to protect,
if deemed suitable.
Ayhan Agha.
Your gold is not enough for me. How much gold do you have?
I mean, I have so much gold that even the pharaoh
can only dream about it. And it is at your service, Osman Bey.
Praise be, Ayhan Agha, thank you.
Gold or gold coins are the least we can
give to the leader of ummah, Bayindir Bey.
Is that so?
Very well.
Them prepare your gold.
I'll ask for it when needed.
Goodbye.
-Bayindir.
-My Bey.
Send an Alp after him, find out what he is up to.
Yes, my Bey. Yes, but
did Ayhan Agha do something wrong?
We don't know who is the friend and who is the enemy.
Until then, he will be deemed suspicious.
Look, he had been informed before everyone else.
Obviously he is watching us. We will see.
Was it because he is a trader or traitor?
Yes, my Bey.
This is Bayindir Bey's warehouse.
There might be something wrong, my Shahzade.
There's only one way to find that out.
-Aykurt.
-Come on.
Open it.
Search everywhere, come on.
My Shahzade, there's servant outfit.
Thankfully, there's no gold in the cottage.
Thankfully.
Open it.
How could Bayindir Bey do this?
I don't want to make assumptions,
but it seems Bayindir Bey's desire for gold made him blind.
You shed the blood of my alps on my treasure.
Whoever did this
he will pay for this heavily.
I swear, whoever did this
in the middle of this hall
I'll cut his head off.
Yakup Bey and others are coming, my Bey.
Yakup Bey, Saadet Hatun.
-Welcome.
I'm so sorry to hear the incident, Malhun Hatun.
-Thank you.
-A friend in need is a friend indeed.
Of course we'd come.
Shahzade Alaeddin, Boran brother will get better, right?
Of course he will get better I hope,
don't be sad.
Saadet Hatun. Let's have a seat.
Osman Bey is in the council you may come, Yakup Bey.
This is a huge weakness Malhun Hatun.
But you'll learn from it. The palace is not like a tent.
Precautions must be taken for every person
that goes in and out.
The bigger the trouble is, the more the enemies are.
Of course, Gonca Hatun.
But we are used to the sneaks in the Frontiers.
That's why we always have an antidote.
We'll surely find out who did this to us
and punish them severely.
You fight with the snakes in the Frontiers
and I fight with the devils with the face of an angel.
You know that snake would hurt and
take precautions accordingly
but there are some people that smile at you
but do dirty tricks behind your back.
You're talking about hypocrisy, you're right,
Saadet Hatun.
May Allah protect us all from their wrath.
-Welcome to your palace, Bala Hatun.
-You welcome too.
Welcome, Bala.
Have a seat.
We have never met in person before
but I heard a lot about you.
What are you going to say, Osman Bey?
You tried to do something you cannot handle.
You'll embarrass us all.
Yakup Bey.
Tell me. Did you send those letters to Beys?
Are all the Beys ready for the battle
we will make with Mongols?
Everyone has to do his part.
We will not pay the tax
and we will form an army.
Wouldn't Mongol intelligence find it out?
Do you want to ruin these lands?
While we have a Bey like you,
we don't even need an enemy.
Yakup Bey.
When you told me to pay that tax,
my palace was raided.
Now, should I consider this as a game as well?
What are saying, Osman Bey?
Is that what you think?
If I thought so,
...you wouldn't be in my council with me.
What I'm saying now is...
You should trust me about the gold matter.
I'll take care of it.
Thank you.
And I'll start our moves against Mongolians.
So tell me now.
How many horsemen can you prepare?
Sorry for your trouble.
You're alright now, aren't you?
I'm good. How are you?
Your arrival in the frontiers was so sudden.
Have you got used to it?
Thankfully, Malhun Hatun helped us feel at home here.
Right?
Yes, Saadet Hatun.
Saadet Hatun is good at...
...seeing everywhere like her own home.
She never feels like a stranger.
You two have a tough challenge, hatuns.
Being two hatuns in one house.
It's our challenge, Saadet Hatun.
Everyone has a different challenge.
-Of course, we should...
-Of course.
Of course. But I wouldn’t..
...let it happen.
Bala Hatun, are you alright?
-Water! Bring warm water!
-Bala.
I'm good. I'm fine.
I'm wayworn. Sorry for this.
I should rest.
-Bala! Bala! Hatuns!
-Bala Hatun!
Take her to her room quickly! Come on!
Mother, we should let father know.
Be patient, dear. When she wakes up, we will.
He's dealing with problems now. Slowly. Slowly.
Ulgen.
You go to the market place.
Carry the gold to the treasure room!
My Shahzade.
Praise be to you and the alps!
You took the gold back from
those traitors!
We got the gold. Now we have to expose
the traitor among us.
Well... When he shows up I'll
choke him to death!
Tell me, my Shahzade.
Where did you find the gold?
The traitor must have left
some evidence behind.
-Evidence..
-Yes.
He left evidence, Bayindir Bey. But...
We'll tell only Osman Bey
about the evidence.
What are you saying, my Shahzade?
We have a spy among us?
Yes, sure. A huge palace.
Many go in and out.
You're right, my Shahzade. We shouldn't
talk about this in a public place.
You are right. We should never talk
in public places.
-Bayindir Bey.
-Yes?
-Where is Osman Bey?
-He must be in the council.
My Shahzade, my Bey will be happy to
hear the good news.
-Let's go.
-Bayindir Bey.
You stay here.
My Shahzade, shall we hold Bayindir Bey?
Not now. Get the gates closed.
-Don't let him go anywhere.
-As you order, my Shahzade.
Oguz, hold the gates.
-What's the situation.
-We looked everywhere in the palace, Konur Bey.
-Except for the rooms of Beys.
-Search the rooms of Beys too.
It's an important matter.
I'll search Bayindir Bey's room.
You get to the other rooms.
Why is this gold in Bayindir Bey's room?
You trust your warriors so much,
Osman Bey.
If Allah permits...
...our alps won't have to test each other
in the battlefield one day.
Then you'll see if your 10.000 men...
...are equal to 100.00 or not.
When the beys we're expecting arrive,
...we won't test each other...
...but slaughter the heathens.
There is no victor except Allah!
You're right.
Do I have permission, my Bey?
Come in, Orhan!
-My Bey.
-Speak.
Excuse usz Yakup Bey.
There is an important matter.
You may leave, Osman Bey.
-Baysungur.
-My Bey.
-Take care of Yakup Bey.
-As you order, my Bey.
You didn't come back with empty hands, did you?
I didn't, my Bey. All the gold is in the palace now.
Why do you have a sullen face?
Where we found the gold...
It's Bayindir Bey's house.
What are you saying, Orhan? It can't be him.
-There must be a game.
-Those who took the gold from Yenisehir...
They removed their trails.
But we detected them, my Bey.
The trails led us to Bayindir Bey's house.
And, my Bey...
The clothes of those who attacked were in the same place.
What are you saying, son?
It can't be true.
Someone who knew must have put them.
Someone is pulling a trick.
Bayindir can't...
...have got Boran shot. For gold? No.
Bayindir? No.
My Bey.
-All the palace was search.
-And?
These pouches are from the treasure.
But we found them in Bayindir Bey's room.
-Orhan.
-My Bey.
Bring Bayindir to me.
He'll be in front of my eyes until the truth is revealed.
As you order, my Bey.
The gold has been found! There is no problem anymore.
Thanks to Allah, Osman Bey. Thanks to Allah.
But it's not enough.
Did you find who performed the betrayal?
Yes, we did! We did!
Good. Good.
You should behead him immediately.
In such a betrayal
...the traitor should be beheaded.
Yakup Bey.
We are struggling to become a state here.
I can say the words to give death sentence easily.
But I intend to serve justice...
...with a court, a judge...
..and with evidence.
Not with the words a Bey says,
...but with the justice itself.
You say you will set a court and let it decide, huh?
You intended to take the gold, Yakup Bey.
The problem has been solved.
The rest is my internal matter.
-Let me see you off.
-No.
If you insist on a court,
..I will attend as the Sultan.
Since the day when you pledged loyalty,
there has been no internal or external, Osman Bey.
Let's see how the justice will be served.
When we have the court,
...you will see the justice for yourself.
You will see.
Here, here.
Wonder how happy Osman Bey got,
after receiving the good news.
My Shahzada, who knows how proud of you he is.
Arrest Bayindir Bey.
Bayindir Bey, you are guilty of..
Stealing the treasure, wounding Boran Bey
and murdering our Alps.
What are you saying my Shahzada?
-What gold? What murdering?
-Evidence is clear.
The golds have been found in your quarters, not only that..
The same golds have been found in
your room as well, Bayindir Bey.
Perish the thought. That is slander.
Do I even need gold.
How am I to accuse for wounding Boran,
my brother, my comrade.
You all know me. It is me Bayindir of Cavundur.
Did Yakup Bey convinced you? Or was it for yourself.
Couldn’t you control your nafs, Bayindir Bey?
What Yakup Bey? What nafs?
Don't do it, my Shahzada.
Take him to prison.
Take my head, my Shahzada.
Take my head instead of putting this dirt to my name.
Let them not say Bayindir has sold his cause.
Do not be late.
Give the medicine I prepared to Boran Bey every hour.
-Couple of drops would be enough.
-As you command, my Shahzada.
Alright, go.
Alaeddin Bey.
Look who is here.
So you wander around as a healer today.
I Wonder what you'll be tomorrow.
I'll take that as a compliment.
You have a lot of confidence. However..
This much is no good. Let me tell you that.
You don't seem so angry today.
Did you start drinking camomile tea,
Trickster Hatun?
-Scholar..
-Got it, you didn't.
However, I told you to drink once a day.
This anger of yours, is no good.
Howver, my duty calls. With your permission,
Trickster Hatun.
Is Bala Hatun okay?
Did something happen to my mother?
She passed out, they took her to her room.
What are you saying?
Tell me, Kismet. How is she?
She has fever. She must've got cold coming here.
After resting a bit, she will get better.
I had them make soup from bone broth.
It will help her get better I hope.
I hope so.
Kismet.
-Malhun.
-Bala.
Thank Allah, she is getting better. Are you alright?
I am alright.
Mother.
Mother, are you alright?
Thank Allah she is alright. Don't worry.
So, what happened? Father
told me you were alright?
She got tired on the road.
She is alright now though, look.
I am alright. Don't worry.
Alright, be good mother.
Kismet Hatun, boil cassidony.
I already did my Shahzada.
I will bring it now.
Do not hinder it. You will drink it until
you get better, alright mother?
I am alright.
Look I don't want to come here
because of this.
I made you all worried.
Don't say this Bala. Of course we be worried.
You got up fast thinking that
you got better, mother.
You will be away from Alaca a little bit more.
Right, Kismet Hatun?
Are we allowed in, my Bey?
Come.
-I didn't do anything my Bey.
-Get out!
You say you didn't do anything.
But everything comes out of your room.
My Bey. Someone is playing trickery.
When did you go to your post last time?
My Bey, it has been years. It is also just sitting empty.
You say it is emtpy. However, it was full when Alps arrived.
All of our treasure was there.
Don't do it my Bey.
How many people know this.
Not many, only Alps.
What about this?
My Bey, it is certain that who plays the trickery plays it well.
My Bey.
May Allah help you as you did to me.
You were there in my worst times.
You took my by your side. So I knew your cause as mine.
I never doubted you once.
I spilled my blood..
To realize your dream. My Bey..
Do you really believe that I would betray you?
After all these years.
After all this time.
I want to believe not to your act..
But to your word.
However, I believe in court evidence.
Here..
Evidence is there.
My Bey, I know your justice the best.
If no one knows, I do.
My Bey, like every sinner, I am scared of death as well.
I am, however..
If you think that I am a traitor..
I do not want to live. Take my head.
No.
No. What I believe won't change anything.
There will be a court.
If a head has to be taken..
Justice will decide that.
Alps!
Take him.
My son, you will find out if Bayindir has to do with this.
Until tomorrow's court.
What do you want me to do, Bey Father?
You will check everything again and again, thoroughly.
What's on your mind
His mind is on Mother Bala, Bey Father.
What happened to Bala? Mother Bala is here, in the palace.
However, she is not well.
-She passed out this morning, father.
-What are you saying.
You see? Bala fell ill.
And Malhun did not even let Osman know.
So, mother. Your work is easy.
What is easier than set two hatun against each other.
It is not like that, son.
Both of them fought for beylik.
I saw it in their eyes.
Bala is the daughte of a sheikh.
She got her manners from her father.
She says alright to everything.
Malhun, is the daughter of Bey. She is smart.
She came to this house knowing her challenges.
What will you do, mother?
This work falls upon you my valiant.
Neither Bala nor Malhun.
We first act on Orhan.
You want to take revenge for your spilled blood, right?
-Tell me to hit and I'll do it.
-No.
We'll do such a thing to Orhan that
there won't be any blood but it will be painful.
I sent a letter to Holofira and invited
her to the marketplace.
She's a beautiful girl, she must be good at trade as well.
If you marry Holofira,
our trade with the lords will get better.
We will gain the trust of Christian people.
And it will make Orhan go crazy.
When he breaks up with Holofira because of her mother
and when we take Holofira,
he will even be the enemy of his own household.
Holofira.
Saadet Hatun invites me to the frontier marketplace.
Are you going to go, princess?
I'm not sure if I should.
Seeing Orhan does not help me at all.
Princess, are you still...
It doesn't matter.
Orhan didn't even say farewell.
He loves his family more than everyone else.
Especially his mother.
His family does not want you, but
If Orhan Bey really loves you
he wouldn't listen to anyone else,
and he wouldn't send you away, right?
I don't know.
His eyes still look the same, but...
...how can someone believe that one’s in love with her?
It's a difficult question, princess.
Tell the soldiers to get ready. We'll set out.
There will be court order in the hall. Everyone knows his part.
My Shahzade, what if Yakup Bey is involved in this?
They are in our palace during the court.
If they are responsible for what happened,
I'll punish them all in this hall.
Did you find the gold, Orhan Bey?
We did, we did, Mehmed Bey.
When did we leave something that belongs to us?
We will punish the one who stole it as well.
And you're boasting with it.
Your palace was raided, someone inside you betrayed you...
You're not even sure about your Bey's loyalty
but you're dreaming about establishing a state.
You should be ashamed.
What we have is so great that
even the inside man's going after it
and the outsider.
Are you jealous of
what you can't achieve, Mehmed... Bey?
What are you going to do Orhan?
Will you do your job secretly and disguise
yourself as someone else?
No. Making vile plans
is your thing.
Wash your hands before throwing mud at somebody.
When we are on bad terms
you’ll feel the cold of my sword, don't worry about it.
-Orhan!
-Mehmed!
My Shahzade.
Wait.
He's our guest.
Keep an eye on your Shahzade, Konur Bey.
Otherwise when he dies, you will not
be able to explain it to Osman Bey.
Or you can't go to your Osman Bey at all.
You need to be brave at the right time,
don't trust your youthfulness and waste yourself.
Bala, my Bala.
-Are you alright?
-I'm alright.
Children told me that you fainted and
I saw you lying on the ground...
-You're alright, right?
Among all those things
I'm bothering you as well, right?
Of course not, look at me don't say such things.
You can only be my crown.
You can only be the crown.
Look at me, you are alright, right?
Your sickness did not relapse, right?
I'm alright my Osman.
I couldn't stay when I heard about the raid.
I wanted to be with you, but
I guess riding the horse tired me out.
Very well. Just get better,
I'm well when you are well.
This situation makes me think, my Osman.
The enemy tries to surround us all around.
It is time to vigilant all the time.
That's why
you'll stay in Sogut.
The defense of Sogut is very important, if you stay there
I'll not worry.
Of course, my Bey. Sogut is our first.
My sheikh, my father's breath is there,
I'll protect it at all costs.
-May I come in, my Bey?
-Come on in, son.
Praise be! Praise be!
Thanks to Allah, mother.
Thanks to Allah.
As I see you like this, I feel like I am getting stronger.
My brave son...
If I am standing here right now, it is thanks to you.
You'll be alright mother.
You'll be alright if Allah permits.
-I am alright.
-My Bey father.
-I found something, but..
-What is it?
They did not leave any tracks, but..
...they left this.
We took this out from our injured Alps.
Our healers had it.
This is not one of our arrows, my Bey.
This belongs to infidels.
I went to Boran Bey. I looked at his wounds.
Those wounds could not be caused by our swords.
Those were infidel daggers, my Bey father.
This proof is not enough.
Dig the graves of dogs who died here. Right now.
Yes my Bey.
Attention! Osman Bey!
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you too.
Here, Yakub Bey.
On the 23rd day of the month of Rabul Ahir...
..a bad incident took place in Yenisehir.
Today the truth will be revealed.
O, Muslim people.
VAIIahi, I swear I did not betray.
If I have any fault, it is not being able to arrive on time...
...and help my companions, my brother Boran.
Silence, Bayindir Bey, silence.
First the court will speak, witnesses will be heard...
..evidence will be seen.
Orhan Bey, explain what you saw before the court.
Yes, dear judge.
We, with the word of Veysel, traced them.
Then the tracks took us to the house of Bayindir Bey.
The house...
Yes dear judge.
The gold was found in Bayindir Bey's room.
I didn't want to bring someone under suspicion.
I told you what I heard.
This is what it is.
Bayindir Bey, is the place mentioned yours?
Yes, it is mine, dear judge.
But I don't know about the rest.
I don't know about the gold or the treasure.
Have you seen that move all by yourself?
Is there anyone behind this?
Dear judge. I am telling you that I am innocent...
-But you are trying to learn if I have any partners.
-Bayindir Bey!
Everyone knows how much you love gold.
What do you want to do by hiding your guilt?
Son.
This is the place of justice.
Everyone...
...can be judged because of their actions.
Not their past.
Be quiet.
My Shahzade...
The love I had for gold..
...was unfortunately an impossible love.
Long time ago, I gave up on that love.
But what can I do? It did not give up on me.
It was in my destiny to fall because of that.
Maybe it is the sin of what you did in your past.
Osman Bey... Did you witness the incident?
No.
Just..
...just the things I heard here.
Yakub Bey... Did you hear something?
It happened in this palace.
How can I hear the thing
Osman Bey does not know, dear judge?
I do not know.
Is there anyone who can witness
for the benefit Bayindir Bey?
Come on, my son.
Come on! Come on! It's about Bayindir Bey's life! Come on!
My Shahzade!
Come on!
Then... we need to make a decision.
It was in my destiny to fall because of a
slander despite my innocence.
O, the Ummah of Muhammad (PBUH).
If I did anything good for you...
...I am giving you all my pardon in this world and Qiyamah.
But... I want one
thing from my Allah..
Do not remember me as a traitor.
Clerk Efendi. Note the date.
Now it is time to announce the decision.
The finger cut by sharia does not hurt.
I can sacrifice myself for your justice, dear judge.
Now it is time to hear the decision, Malhun Hatun.
The evidence was confirmed.
Bayindir Bey's guilt was proven because
the stolen gold was found in his house...
...and the same gold was found in...
...his room during the search.
His guilt is proven by the testimony of the
Beys and the Alps.
Because of the theft and the amount of gold stolen...
...his hand must be cut off, and...
...because of the blood shed from our martyred Alps,
Bayindir Bey...
..is sentenced to death.
Implement the decision.
Are you sure about your decision, dear judge?
Yes, in the light of the evidence.
Do you allow me, Osman Bey?
I do not.
Dear judge.
If you allow me..
I want to carry out his execution.
Such a pity, he was a brave man.
Come on.
I believe your innocence.
Alhamdulillah.
Take my head. Alhamdulillah.
I bear witness that there is none worthy of
worship except Allah,
I bear witness that
Muhammad is the Messenger of Allah,
Come on son. Come on.
Stop!
Thankfully.
Dear judge, my Bey. Bayindir Bey is innocent!
-What's your proof Alaeddin Bey?
-Alps!
They all have the same trace in the same place
but they hid one of them.
-Bayindir Bey is innocent.
-Yes, he is.
Thankfully!
That's my boy.
Dear judge.
The attackers were the crusaders.
They obviously set a trap.
Their goal is not the treasure alone,
they want us to fight with each other.
My Bey, then they set a trap for me as well.
They left me alive for me to inform you back.
Both the sword and arrow aimed at Boran Bey
came from the crusaders.
The ones who stole the gold as well.
It is clear that Bayindir Bey is innocent
considering the proof Alaeedin Bey brought.
Give me your pardon, Bayindir Bey.
Instant judgment is not good,
right Saadet Hatun?
Since his own Bey didn't believe him,
we had to doubt as well.
But thank Allah, it is better this way.
Otherwise a great Bey would have been
died because of the lack of perception.
Since the justice has been secured
we should leave, Osman Bey.
Do your duty in an honest way just like your justice.
Have a safe journey.
Don't worry, whoever set this trap
I swear they will be ruined.
Thank you, Osman Bey!
Osman!
Rejoice all you want, Osman.
Rejoice because Bayindir was saved.
But I'll put an end to your joy.
Make the preparations, we'll make a bloodshed
in Sogut in two days.
This time, I'll stick my dagger to
Osman's heart.
We'll incite the people in Sogut and cause a rebellion, right?
Not rebellion Vasilis we'll make a raid.
As honorable Christian soldiers, as Crusaders,
we'll make a bloodshed in Sogut.
For that reason, someone has to sneak our soldiers inside.
Tesellius.
He's been living in Sogut for years.
They know him as Hasan Agha.
-They trust him a lot.
-Hasan Agha.
You'll sneak our soldiers in Tesellius.
Excuse me, Master Gera.
But why do we set Christians as target
instead of causing a secret rebellion inside.
In order to unite Christians and lords Vasilis.
This is not just our war.
This is the war of cross and crescent!
After our raid, all of the lords will unite.
The slaughter we will start in Sogut will spread,
Everywhere Muslims breathe
Bilecik,
Inegol, Karacahisar,
everywhere Muslims breathe...
The enemy is concerned about our unity,
that's for sure.
But thanks to my Creator,
He helped us ruin this plan.
-Thankfully.
And it was so crucial that there couldn't even
be a single doubt among us.
But we were patient until the end.
Thanks to my Rabb, He showed us the truth.
So, Bayindir, since they made the plan through you,
then it will be your duty to find them.
For sure, my Bey.
Thanks to my Rabb Who brought us together again.
-Thanks to Him.
Come on then, enjoy your food.
In the name of Allah, the merciful,
the compassionate.
We would be happier if Boran was here.
Boran.
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you too!
Praise be! You got up, is that so?
-Brother, are you better?
-I'm alright my Bey.
-Of course I'd join such a table.
-Praise be! come on.
Come here.
Since Boran is here, now we can
rejoice twice as much
-Let us have it then.
-Thank Allah, thank Allah.
Enjoy.
Then my Bey, it is now time for our..
Double weddings.
-Right, Bala?
-Yes.
It is time. Right, Shahzadas?
There is still time.
Do you want to get rid of us?
Look here, look here.
You made your mothers tired enough.
Let other hatuns take care of your problems.
That is near as well, my Bey.
We've sent word to all around.
We're looking for brides that are fit for
our Shahzadas.
What are you looking for?
Both of their brides are ready.
-And..
-Sister.
You must be hungry.
Go ahead and eat.
Let her eat a lot and speak less.
Osman's little son is quite clever.
He is not like his brother.
He is, mother.
However, why are we talking about this.
The grandson of Sheikh Edebali.
He has Ahi Community with him.
And sisters. From what I heard people like him as well.
Yes, mother.
Alaeddin's heart is nearly falling for you, Gonca.
-What are you saying, dear mother?
-You heard what I said.
I saw how he looked at you.
Mother, I..
You will make Alaeddin fall for you, Gonca.
You will make him love you so much..
That he will do everything you say.
-Mother, what are you saying?
-You heard what I said, Gonca.
You are a smart girl.
You know what to do.
Do not.
Do not, Gonca, fall for him.
I know that you do not show weakness, however..
It is duty, understood?
As you command, mother.
You will have a cart of supplies prepared tomorrow.
You will take it to Sogut, Bala Hatun.
Make way! Osman Bey!
Alps are ready Bey. Scouts are on their way too.
-The roads are ready too.
-Thank you, thank you.
May you travel swiftly Bey. Come as you go.
And bring joy with good news,
if Allah permits.
Thank you, thank you.
Do not worry.
Bala, do not try to ride a horse
before completely healing.
Do not worry Bey. May you come back swiftly.
-Thank you, thank you. Alright then.
-My Bey.
I don't feel at ease.
I want to come with you if you allow it.
We do not know what this
Mongolian dog will do.
My brother is right, Bey. I want to come with you too.
No, my sons. You have a greater task.
You will stay here as my eyes.
Now, hear me well.
While I'm gone..
You will be in charge of the palace.
Look..
Do not act careless today in the court.
Do not decide on anything before making sure.
As you command, Bey.
Do not worry Bey Father.
I will lead well if Allah permits.
May you travel swiftly.
I do not worry son. Palace is in your hands.
Son.
You will go to Sogut.
You are entrusted with your mother as well.
I will do my best father.
May you travel swiftly, if Allah permits.
Thank you. Thank you to all.
Time for me to go.
GERMIYANOGULLARI BORDER - FRONTIER BAZAAR
So Orhan Bey. You lead the Beys for now.
-How do you feel, brother?
-Want to know how it is?
It is like I carry all the weight of
Yenisehir on my shoulders.
You need a hatun to share that weight brother,
don't handle it alone.
-Sister.
-Don't get mad at me.
My mother sent word to all around,
she is looking for a bride.
Malhun Hatun.
You look very busy these days, however..
Come to me when you're free.
I have things to talk with you.
What happened Saadet Hatun. If it is so important,
say it here.
Do not tire me.
Every matter has a place and a time
to be talked about.
You will punish the hatuns who
made this disaster of rugs.
-What are you saying Saadet Hatun?
-You heard what I said.
I can not allow such disrespect on my lands.
Saadet Hatun.
It was your Alps, who collect
all the goods like there's a fire.
It is their fault. And wasn't that paid for already?
Malhun Hatun. I told you this is not the time.
Our matter is different now.
Cerkutay Bey. Introduce our new merchant.
My mother, I will go if you allow me.
Alright, son.
Now hear me well. All of you..
Meet with the new merchant of our bazaar.
Holofira Hatun!
Holofira?
I wish you good luck with your new bench,
Holofira Hatun.
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you too.
May it be easy Hasan Agha, what's your load?
Let me see.
I've brought wheat, here, take a look.
Here it is.
-What about the others?
-Legumes and such.
-Here, you may enter Hasan Agha.
-Thank you.
My Hatun, you don't stop at all.
I lose my power when I lie down, Kismet.
I'll sleep when I get tired.
I promised my Osman Bey, if you don't get rest,
I'll have to inform him.
Look at you.
May Allah bless you Bala Hatun.
You're my aide, why would someone report her Hatun?
Come on.
-Peace be upon you Bala Hatun.
-Peace be upon you too. Welcome.
Thank you. My mother send her regards,
she sent this for the soup kitchen.
Thank you. May Allah bless her.
This is my mother Saadet Hatun's gift,
we owe Alaeddin Bey our lives.
Thanks. Saadet Hatun is very thoughtful.
-Sogut is such a peaceful place.
-It is.
Sogut is not like any other place.
If you'll excuse me, I want to help with something as well.
Of course, if you want to do so.
Kismet Hatun.
Here. Praise be!
I feel ashamed to breath when I see people starving.
That's right.
However, all of them are challenges.
Poverty, wealth are challenges of humanity.
Forgetting what Allah has given you,
and thinking all you own is yours.
That is why, it is hard to give.
However, sharing is caring.
Since you know caring, you can come
whenever you want, Gonca Hatun.
Of course I will.
Mother, didn't we send you to Sogut to rest?
Look here, I feel very well here.
Don't stand around, come on and help us.
-Mother.
-Quickly.
-Come on my son, hold it.
-Alright.
Strength to your elbow, Trickster Hatun.
To you too, Scholar.
This is yours.
What is this? You bought me a gift?
My mother is grateful to you for
what you've done for my brother.
You're welcome. But I don't have space right now.
I am a messenger. You can give it back to my mother
if you don't want it.
Alright, let it be.
We're starting.
We crusaders will bring the end of
the crescent ourselves.
Come on.
In the well that welcomed Hadhrat Yusuf..
Were made from rocks like you.
Who knows what kind of soldiers and beys..
Went from this place, and couldn't see the
well by looking at rocks.
Couldn't see and greet.
As it is not proper to go without greeting.
It is not.
Peace be upon you.
Dervish Effendi, strength to your elbow.
Peace be upon you too.
Thank you.
Dervish Effendi.
-Our paths crossed again.
-Indeed.
-Thank you.
-Alps, come here.
Come here. So..
You did not let us to be ashamed against ants
in the other side before.
If you allow me, we would like to help you
carry these rocks to there together.
Looks like your load is heavy, your load is long.
Don't bother.
It will not bother us at all. Quickly, Alps.
Come on.
-Here.
-Thank you, thank you.
If Allah grants us with completing the well...
...next time, you will drink
from the well, if Allah permits.
I hope so, I hope so.
I asked your name when we met earlier...
...but you told me not to ask what you run away from.
Therefore, therefore, I won't ask your name.
I hope I will be granted
with drinking water from this well...
...and I hope I'll see you again.
-If Allah permits.
-Thus..
..we should go for now.
This poor man wants to give you some equipage.
-No, we have food.
-It is not a material...
...it is a meaning, if you accept it.
We always need that. Of course we want it.
Our Master (PBUH)...
...one of the days when he felt that the
migration to the other world was approaching...
...he went to the masjid.
His intention was to ask for his sahabas' pardon.
He could hardly stand with the help of
a sahaba. He calls out to his sahabas...
"O my Sabahas,
if anyone has any rights on me...
...let him speak."
No one speaks.
He says it for the second time.
Again, no one speaks.
After that, the Messenger of Allah calls out again.
A sahaba from the back stands up.
The name of...
...this sahaba is Ukkasha (R.A.).
Ukkasha says: O Messenger of Allah...
...you wanted to ride your camel in Hudaybiyyah,
I reached my hand to you.
You got on the camel, then while you were trying
to hit the camel with your whip...
...that whip hit my back. Now,
isn't this my right on you?
The Messenger of Allah says,
Oh Ukkasha...
...this is certainly your right.
Omer (RA) stands up in anger.
Our Prophet says,
"O Omer, do not interfere."
"This is my account."
Then Abu Bakr (RA) stands up and says,
"O Ukkasha...
I will give you as much property as you want.
Come and stop this madness."
Our Efendi says,
"O Abu Bakr, this is my account.
Don't interfere." Sahabas were also
trying hard not to say something.
Our Prophet turned to Ali (RA) and said,
"My daughter Fatima has that whip.
Go and bring that."
When Ali...
...explained the situation,
our mother Fatima became very sad.
"Don't you know that he is ill? Wasn't there someone
among you who could replace him?" she asked.
Then she sent Hasan and Hussein
who were children back then.
When Hasan and Hussein,
the dear grandchildren of our Prophet...
...entered the masjid, they went to
Ukkasha and said, "O Ukkasha...
...do not hit our grandfather.
Hit us. Let us pay for it."
Our Efendi says,
"How can I hurt you?...
...Besides,
this is my account."
The whip had come.
Sahabas were even more upset.
Our Efendi orders them to give the whip to Ukkasha.
When Ukkasha says, "O, Messenger of Allah,
when you hit with that whip..
...I did not have any clothes on my back.
Is that also my right on you?" Sahabas stand up.
Our Efendi calms them down and says
"Ukkasha is right."
He leaves the minbar, takes his shirt off
and waits for Ukkasha to hit with his whip.
Ukkasha raises the whip and then...
...he kissed the seal of prophethood of the
Messenger of Allah between his shoulder bones.
And in tears, he says "O Messenger of Allah...
I give my pardon to you. I can sacrifice
my mother and father for you."
That's what our Prophet, our guide did.
Justice is for everyone.
Take the stick and hit with
it to take what you want.
Hit, so justice will prevail.
Hit, so justice can come.
Raid! Raid!
Come on, brothers! It is time to take our revenge!
It is time to take what is ours!
Burn it down! Come on!
Burn them!
-Raid!
-Alps! My Shahzade!
My Shahzade, crusaders raided our place.
Come in! Come in!
Come on! Everyone inside!
Come on!
Come on! To the kitchen!
Come in! Go in there!
Come on! Gonca, go in there!
I will stay, Scholar. Come on!
Mother, go inside! You were entrusted to me!
Sogut is entrusted to me, my son! We turned everyone
who tried to burn Sogut into ashes.
We will do it again for sure.
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
Wait! Wait!
Look... Take your hand off or I will break your hand.
Wait!
Stop!
Welcome Osman Bey.
Call your Commander.
I see that you are always angry.
But do not speak loudly when talking to the Commander.
Our anger is not towards a place or a person.
We are angry because of the situation you put us in.
Come on!
Call your Commander! I brought the gold.
Where is the Commander?
I am the Commander, Osman Bey.
-Alright.
-Sit down.
I came to your table to get to know you better.
You didn't even give me a piece of food.
-Sit down. Eat.
-I did not come here to eat.
I will give you the gold and leave.
Sure, you will give the gold.
But don't be so sure about leaving.
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
e will burn it down! We will not show mercy on anyone!
You are the ones who will breathe
for the last time you dastards! Alps!
Allah is the Greatest!
-Mother, do not stay here!
-I will not leave the entrustment, my son.
Recite salaah. We are fighting!
Protect Bala Hatun.
Victory belongs to those who believe Allah.
Allah is the Greatest!
Who does this gold belong to, Osman?
Are you going to give me what is mine?
-This gold belongs to Konya, Osman.
-This is the gold that I inherited.
How is that yours?
I am Akcelasun.
Konya is mine, the palace is mine.
Why would the gold be yours, Osman?
Nokers! Arrest him!
You came to our land..
...and tried to rule the lands which did not
belong to you with cruelty!
But you will learn. You will learn...
The wolves are never slaves, they are always
the ones who question others.
Do you think you can survive here if you kill me?
It is not your concern, but mine
Contact: turkision@gmail.com